

1. seo best practices is preferred: SEO stands for Search Engine Optimization, which is the practice of increasing the quantity and quality of traffic to your website through organic search engine results.
2. Write clean CSS using layout methods such as flexbox and grid: The basic difference between CSS Grid Layout and CSS Flexbox Layout is that flexbox was designed for layout in one dimension - either a row or a column. Grid was designed for two-dimensional layout - rows, and columns at the same time.  
3.Experience with Sass is a plus: Sass: Syntactically Awesome Style Sheets, Sass is a preprocessor scripting language that is interpreted or compiled into Cascading Style Sheets. SassScript is the scripting language itself.CSS with superpowers. Sass is the most mature, stable, and powerful professional grade CSS extension language in the world.
4. ES6+ syntax: ES6 brought significant changes to the JavaScript language. It introduces several new features such as, block-scoped variables, new loop for iterating over arrays and objects, template literals, and many other enhancements to make JavaScript programming easier and more fun
5. The ability to write vanilla JavaScript without the use of jQuery: VanillaJS is a name to refer to using plain JavaScript without any additional libraries like jQuery back in the days. People use it as a joke to remind other developers that many things can be done nowadays without the need for additional JavaScript libraries.
6. Experience with the WordPress REST API : There are many ways to create an API. A REST (Representational State Transfer) API is a particular type that is developed following specific rules. In other words, REST presents a set of guidelines developers can use when building APIs. This ensures that the APIs function effectively.
7. Implement custom post types and plug-ins in WordPress: Custom post types are used to convert a regular WordPress website into a content management system. As the name suggests, you can use custom post types to create a variety of different content types for your website.
 A plugin is a piece of software containing a group of functions that can be added to a WordPress website. They can extend functionality or add new features to your WordPress websites.
8. Gutenberg block editor: Gutenberg, alternatively known as the “WordPress block editor” or just the “WordPress editor,” is the WordPress content editor introduced in WordPress 5.0, released on December 6, 2018. If you haven't heard that term, it's the default editor that all WordPress sites use unless you've specifically disabled it.
9. npm modules : npm is the world's largest Software Registry. The registry contains over 800,000 code packages. Open-source developers use npm to share software. Many organizations also use npm to manage private development.
10. Babel and Webpack: Babel is a transpiler for ES6 to ES5, so that browser can understand the JS. Webpack is a bundler for JS and other files that creates bundled file that the users browser can download.
11. Typescript and NextJS: TypeScript is a superset of JavaScript that increases your code quality with types. TypeScript and Next. js are a match made in heaven. Next's features make building full-stack React apps easier than ever, and TypeScript's type system helps you catch errors during development.
12.Single Page Applications (SPA): A single-page application (SPA) is a web application or website that interacts with the user by dynamically rewriting the current web page with new data from the web server, instead of the default method of a web browser loading entire new pages. The goal is faster transitions that make the website feel more like a native app.

asynchronous, event driven architecture, request handling and RESTful interfaces.
Node.js with Koa
Angular 6+